tapiture.com 2013-12-16

# Contact

Welcome to Tapiture. Whether you are in to tech gadgets, stuff for your home, traveling abroad or just looking good, Tapiture makes it easy to discover, share and buy the best of everything online.

The following document outlines the privacy policy for use of the Tapiture website and its mobile applications. It covers Tapiture’s treatment of personal information that Tapiture gathers when you use our services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Tapiture does not own or contro, or to individuals that Tapiture does not employ or manage. The column on the right provides a short explanation of the terms of use and is not legally binding.

## Purpose

Tapiture, Inc. is committed to respecting the privacy rights of its customers, visitors, and other users of the Tapiture web site at www.tapiture.com, our application on mobile devices and through various third party applications (collectively the “Service”). We created this Privacy Policy to give you notice of how your private information will be used as a result of submitting it to us. This Policy is only applicable to the Service, including any sub-domains, and not to any other web sites that you may be able to access from the Service, each of which may have data collection and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy. When you register with us, the Personally Identifiable Information you provide to us is used to provide the services you have registered for, to deliver email notifications to you, and from time to time, to validate your identity. Our data collection policies allow you to choose how much information you provide to us, and to control how we use that Personally Identifiable Information as set forth below. To find out more, please read on.

The purpose of this Policy is to describe the information collection, use, and dissemination practices of the owners of Tapiture.com, its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates and registered d/b/a companies (Collectively Referred herein after as “Tapiture” or “we” or “us”) and all related web sites owned or registered to Tapiture and applies to Tapiture’s collection, use, storage and disclosure of information by Tapiture on its (a) web sites, including all its divisions, subsidiaries and related companies (collectively, the “Web Site”), (b) on various Third Party web sites, (c) through the Service and (d) to Tapiture’s other information collection, including the acquisition of customer information from third parties. Tapiture is not responsible for the information collection or privacy practices of third party web sites or applications.

Basically,

We need some information but you can control how much you share. We respect you now and will still respect you in the morning, even if you share too much.

## Information Collection, Use, and Dissemination practices.

Depending on the service you are accessing, you could be asked at various times to provide information such as your name, email address, contact phone number, payment information or other information related to the services you are seeking. We request this information to deliver on the services or products you are requesting, and to allow us to provide our strongest value to you - a personalized online experience. Information collected online is often defined as being either anonymous or personally identifiable:

  1. Anonymous Information refers to information that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. For instance, we may know that thousands of people have visited this Privacy Policy web page, but we do not necessarily know their names, where they live, or their date of birth. What we collect from visits such as this constitutes anonymous information. Some of the individuals who access our services decline to use the personalization features that are available to them, and therefore those individuals are anonymous to us and the only data we collect about them is anonymous information.
  2. Personally Identifiable Information refers to information that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name, email address, phone number or payment information. While you can search and browse some sections of our Service without being a registered user, certain activities do require registration. Registering with Tapiture.com using the web form or Login with Facebook or Twitter button will also cause a cookie to be issued; this cookie allows the Tapiture to “recognize” you when you are on our site to allow us to personalize our service for you.

Basically,

We collect information to make Tapiture highly relevant to you. Without this, it would just be a generic website and you may or may not like us.

## Anonymous Information

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We may link this automatically-collected data to certain Personally Identifiable Information. 

We may use third-party tracking services that use cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate. 

Basically,

We have your account data. Our servers also gather log information used to make our services better. We may choose to combine this data to make sure you have a great experience.

## Personally Identifiable Information

In order to use the basic features of this Service, you must register and provide certain personal information. During registration you may be required to give contact information (such as your name, email address, mailing address, social security number, drivers license and credit card information, and telephone or cell phone number). You may also provide us with information that, when combined with Personally Identifiable Information, provides us with a better idea of who you are, including but not limited to your gender, birthday, marital status, and education level. We use this information to connect you with the providers of services in which you have expressed interest. Depending on the services you have chosen to use, some or all of your Personally Identifiable Information may be used by Tapiture.com to provide such services. Personally Identifiable Information may also be provided to intermediaries and third parties who assist us in providing you with the service upon your request. For example, if you register and desire to purchase a product, your personally identifiable information may be provided to one or more prospective sellers (e.g., contact information and payment information). Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, however, Tapiture.com will not rent or sell your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties without your permission.

Tapiture.com is the owner of the information collected through the Service.

Basically,

You give us your info to have an account and buy stuff. Without this information, you wouldn’t enjoy Tapiture (or be able to buy cool new things) and we wouldn’t have much of a business. 

However don’t fear: we take your info seriously and will only use it to help you get what you need out of Tapiture. 

## Sharing Your Information

Tapiture may collect information from you when you provide information to a third party and Tapiture subsequently acquires or uses the information provided by the third party. Such information may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, street address, zip code, telephone numbers (including cell phone numbers and carriers), birth date, gender, salary range, education and marital status, occupation, industry of employment, personal and online interests, and such other information as the you may have provided to the third party. When acquiring this information, Tapiture seeks assurances from the third party that you agreed to provide and have such information acquired by Tapiture. If you did not give express permission, or you would like to remove your permission, you may suppress all of your information by using our convenient [unsubscribe link](mailto:help@tapiture.com).

Basically,

If we send you to a vendor’s site to buy a product, they are going to need some information. If you don’t want to give it to them, you probably didn’t want the product in the first place.

## Other Methods of Collecting Personal Information

Other occasions when Tapiture obtains information from you include (1) your claiming a prize or seeking to redeem an offer by Tapiture or by a third party, (2) your requests for assistance through Tapiture’s customer service department, and (3) when you voluntarily subscribe to a Tapiture service or newsletter.

## Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Information Collected Using Technology

Tapiture currently uses cookie and web beacon technology to associate certain Internet-related information about you with information about you in its database. Additionally, Tapiture may use other new and evolving sources of information in the future.

Basically,

Tapiture is for sharing and buying stuff. You cannot use our site to post pornographic material, harass people, send spam and do other crazy stuff. Be reasonable, responsible, and don’t do anything stupid and you’ll be fine.

## Use of Third Party Services

As a part of our Service, Tapiture offers links to web sites operated by various third parties and is not responsible or liable for any acts or omissions created or performed by these third parties. We provide such links for your convenience and reference only. Tapiture does not operate or control in any way any information, software, products or services available on such web sites. Tapiture’s inclusion of a link to a web site does not imply any endorsement of the services or the site, its contents, or its sponsoring organization.

(a) Cookies. “Cookies” are a feature on your browser software. If enabled, we may write cookies that may store small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to any of the pages of this Web Site. Cookies assist us in tracking which of our features appeal the most to you and what content you may have viewed on past visits. When you visit this site again, cookies can enable us to customize our content according to your preferences. We may use cookies to: keep track of the number of return visits to this Web Site; accumulate and report aggregate, statistical information on web site usage; deliver specific content to you based on your interests or past viewing history; save your password for ease of access to our Web Site. You can disable cookies, although the Web Site may not function properly for you. Your browser preferences can be modified to accept or reject all cookies, or request a notification when a cookie is set. You may read more about cookies at http://cookiecentral.com. In order to use all of the features and functionality of Tapiture’s Web Site, you need to accept cookies.

Basically,

To remember you, our service will give you a cookie. This is used to personalize your service. Don’t worry, it’s safe. (nom nom nom)

(b) Web Beacons. A web beacon is a programming code that can be used to display an image on a web page, but can also be used to transfer your unique user identification to a database and associate you with previously acquired information about an individual in a database. This allows Tapiture to track certain web sites you visit. Web beacons are used to track online behavioral habits for marketing purposes to determine products or services you may be interested in. In addition to using web beacons on web pages, Tapiture also uses web beacons in email messages sent to individuals listed in Tapiture’s database.

Basically,

Kind of like a cookie, but different. Again, this helps us improve our service to you through personalization and nothing more.

(c) IP Addresses. Tapiture automatically tracks certain information based upon your behavior on the site. We may use this information to do internal research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on the Web Site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on the Web Site or not), your computer browser information, and your IP address. Your Internet Protocol (“IP”) is a unique Internet “address” which is assigned to you by your Internet Service Provider (“ISP”). For local area network (“LAN”), DSL, or cable modem users, an IP address may be permanently assigned to a particular computer. IP addresses are automatically logged by web servers, collecting information about a user’s traffic patterns. While the IP address does not identify an individual by name, it may, with the cooperation of the ISP, be used to locate and identify an individual using the Web. Your IP address can, however, reveal what geographic area you are connecting from, or which ISP you are using. Finally, other web sites you visit have IP addresses, and we may collect the IP addresses of those web sites and their pages.

Basically,

We occasionally track people via their IP address, but usually only if they’re doing something bad like spamming our members. If this isn’t you, you don’t need to worry.

(d) Computer Profiles. Tapiture may also collect and accumulate other anonymous data which will help us understand and analyze the Internet experience of our visitors. For instance, Tapiture may accumulate visitor data relating to referring domain names, the type of browsers used, operating system software, screen resolutions, color capabilities, browser plug-ins, language settings, cookie preferences, search engine keywords and JavaScript enablement. When you provide us with Personal Identification Information, we are able to use such visitor data to identify you.

Basically,

Again, we believe personalization is good.

(e) Data Analysis. Data Analysis technology may be employed from time to time if used by a Client of Tapiture.

(f) New Technology. The use of technology on the Internet, including cookies and web beacons, is rapidly developing. As a result, Tapiture strongly encourages individuals to revisit this policy for any updates regarding its use of new technology.

Basically,

We may use the latest gizmo to improve our service, and we don’t want to pay lawyers every time we do something new. This clause allows us to do that without spending more money.

## No Information Collected from Children

Tapiture will never knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 18. If Tapiture obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 18, that information will be immediately deleted from its database. Because it does not collect such information, Tapiture has no such information to use or to disclose to third parties. Tapiture has designed this policy in order to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”).

Basically,

“Leave them kids alone…”

## Credit Card or Bank Information

Tapiture may, in certain instances, collect credit card numbers or banking numbers and related information when an individual places an order through Tapiture. When the credit card information or banking information is submitted to Tapiture, such information is encrypted and is protected with SSL encryption software. Tapiture will use the credit card or banking information for purposes of processing and completing the requested transaction, and the information will be disclosed to third parties only as necessary to complete the purchase transaction.

Basically,

If you want to buy something, we need a credit card. (duh)

## Use of Individual Information

### General Use

The following paragraphs describe how Tapiture currently uses Personally Identifiable Information, but Tapiture may change or broaden its use at any time. As noted below, Tapiture may update this policy from time to time. Tapiture may use Personally Identifiable Information to provide promotional offers to individuals by means of email advertising, telephone marketing, direct mail marketing, online banner advertising, and package stuffers, among other possible uses.

## Email and Unsubscribe Policy

Tapiture uses Personally Identifiable Information to provide other businesses promotional offers by email to individuals. Tapiture may maintain separate email lists for different purposes. If email recipients wish to end their email subscription from a particular list, they need to follow the instructions at the end of each email message to unsubscribe from the particular list. To unsubscribe from all Tapiture’s email lists, please use our [unsubscribe link](mailto:help@tapiture.com).

Tapiture’s unsubscribe process impacts only the future delivery of electronic mailings disseminated by Tapiture on its own behalf. You may still receive electronic mailings sent on behalf of Third Parties and your personal information may still be shared with Third Parties for use in offline marketing and data appends, including email appends.

You should also note that unsubscribing from Tapiture’s electronic mailings will not automatically unsubscribe the subscriber’s information from any Third Party business associates and licensees of the data. Since Third Party associates and licensee partners maintain separate databases from Tapiture, and you will need to unsubscribe from each source individually, if desired. This allows you the freedom to pick and choose which subscriptions to maintain and which to discontinue.

Basically,

We want to send you emails about things you’ll like. If you don’t like it, unsubscribe. (We’ll still like you, though.) 

## Solicited Email

Tapiture only sends email to individuals who have agreed on the Service to receive email from Tapiture or to individuals who have agreed on a Third Party web site to receive email from Third Parties. As such, Tapiture does not send unsolicited email messages. 

Basically,

We intend to send you emails about things we think you’ll like. If you don’t like it, unsubscribe.

## Targeted Advertising

Tapiture may use Personally Identifiable Information to target advertising to an individual. When an individual is using the Internet, Tapiture uses other information to associate an individual with that person’s Personally Identifiable Information, and Tapiture attempts to show advertising for products and services in which the person has expressed an interest in the Surveys, and otherwise. Tapiture may, at its discretion, target advertising by using email, direct mail, telephones, cell phones, and other means of communication to provide promotional offers.

Basically,

We may choose to have advertising on our site. (Sorry, but we need to make money to stay in business.) We may use your information to improve our advertising performance..

## Wireless Addresses

If the e-mail address you provide to Tapiture is a wireless e-mail or text address, you agree to receive messages at such address from Tapiture or its business associates (unless and until you have elected not to receive such messages by following the instructions in the unsubscribe portion of this policy). You understand that your wireless carrier’s standard rates apply to these messages. You represent that you are the owner or authorized user of the wireless device on which messages will be received, and that you are authorized to approve the applicable charges.

Basically,

If you registered your cell phone, we may send you messages about your account to that number. If your carrier charges you for these messages, change your preferences with us or change your cell phone plan. 

Updated on November 4, 2012
